If you recall from the previous lesson,
إذا تذكرت من الدرس السابق،
iterables are objects that can return one of its elements at a time.
الكائنات المتعددة هي كائنات يمكنها عرض عنصر واحد من عناصرها في كل مرة.
Lists are one of the most common iterables you have used.
القوائم هي أحد أشهر الكائنات المتعددة التي استخدمتها.
It turns out many of the built-in functions we've used so far,
ويبدو أن الكثير من الدوال المضمنة التي استخدمناها حتى الآن،
such as enumerate, returns something called an iterator.
مثل enumerate، تظهر شيئاً يسمى المكرر.
An iterator is an object that represents a stream of data.
والمكرر هو كائن يمثل تياراً من البيانات.
This is different from a list which is also an iterable
وهو يختلف عن القائمة والتي هي كائن متعدد أيضاً
but not an iterator since it is not a stream of data.
لكنها ليست مكرراً بما أنها ليست تياراً من البيانات.
Soon, you'll see some reasons that iterators are favored in different situations.
سترى قريباً بعض الأسباب التي تجعل المكررات مفضلة في حالات مختلفة.
Here we will learn how to create iterators using generators.
سنتعلم هنا كيف ننشئ مكررات باستخدام منشئات.
Generators are a simple way to create iterators using functions.
المنشئات هي طريقة بسيطة لإنشاء مكررات باستخدام الدوال.
However, it's not the only way to create iterators.
لكنها ليست الطريقة الوحيدة لإنشاء المكررات.
You can read more about this in the notes below.
يمكنك قراءة المزيد عن هذا في الملاحظات أدناه.
These terms may be a little confusing.
قد تكون هذه المصطلحات مربكة قليلاً.
The term generator is often used to refer to the generator function,
عادة ما يستخدم مصطلح "المنشئ" للإشارة إلى دالة المنشئ،
but it's also used to refer to the iterator object produced by the function.
لكنه يستخدم أيضاً للإشارة إلى الكائن المكرر الذي تنتجه تلك الدالة.
Here I'll differentiate these by referring to the function as a generator function,
سأميزهما هنا من خلال الإشارة إلى الدالة بمصطلح "دالة المنشئ"،
and what it produces as the iterator.
وإلى ما تنتجه بمصطلح "المكرر".
Here is a generator function called 'my range' that
هذه دالة منشئ واسمها my_range
produces a stream of numbers from zero to x minus one.
تنتج تياراً من الأرقام من 0 إلى س - 1.
Notice that instead of using the return keyword, this uses yield.
لاحظ أنه بدلاً من استخدام الكلمة الرئيسية return، يستخدم هذا المثال yield.
This allows the function to return values one at a time
هذا يسمح للدالة بعرض القيم كل على حدة
and start where it left off each time it's called.
والبدء من حيث توقفت كلما يتم استدعاؤها.
This yield keyword is what differentiates a generator from a typical function.
الكلمة الرئيسية yield هذه هي التي تميّز دالة المنشئ عن دالة عادية.
As you can see here,
كما ترى هنا،
calling my range four returns an iterator that we can then iterate through.
استدعاء my_range(4) يعطي مكرراً يمكننا التكرار من خلاله.
Using a for loop,
باستخدام حلقة for،
we can print values from this stream of data.
يمكننا إظهار قيم من تيار البيانات هذا.
Here this prints zero, one, two and three.
فهي تظهر هنا 0 و1 و2 و3.
In the next section,
في الجزء التالي،
you'll get some practice writing generator functions to create your own iterators
ستتدرب قليلاً على كتابة دوال منشئ لإنشاء مكرراتك الخاصة بك.